OK.
好
Now let's talk about another trick.
我们现在来讨论另一个技巧
When we moved from recognizing isolated signs to recognizing phrases of signs,
我们从识别孤立的手势转为识别手势短语
the combination of movements looks very different.
动作组合看起来非常不同
&gt;&gt; For example, when Thad signed NEED in isolation,
— 例如 Thad 用手势单独表示 NEED 时
his hands started from a rest position and finished in the rest position.
他的双手从静止的位置开始 从静止的位置结束
When he signs NEED in the context of I NEED CAT,
当他表示 I NEED CAT 语境中的 NEED 时
the first part of NEED runs into the last part of I, and
NEED 第一部分跟在 I 最后一部分后面
the last part of NEED runs into the first part of CAT.
NEED 最后一部分后面紧跟着 CAT 第一部分
His hands are no longer moving so much.
他的双手不再移动幅度很大
&gt;&gt; That's right, the signs before and
— 没错 在既定手势前后的手势
after a given sign can significantly affect how it looks.
可以对如何表示它具有重大影响
&gt;&gt; So instead of recognizing the three state model for need,
— 所以这里不是识别 NEED 的三个状态模型
we're going to concatenate a combined six state model of I NEED, and NEED CAT.
我们关注 I NEED 和 NEED CAT 的六个组合状态模型
&gt;&gt; In practice, we often have lots of examples of phrases of sign and
— 在实际中 我们对许多手势短语
not individual signs to train on.
而不是单个手语的短语示例 进行训练
In my original paper on recognizing phrases of ASL, I had 40 signs in
我最初针对识别美式手语的论文中 我有 40 个词语的手语
the vocabulary, but the only training data that I had was 500 phrases,
但是训练的数据是 500 个短语
that each contained five signs.
每个包括 5 个手势
&gt;&gt; In this case,
— 在这种情况下
let's suppose we have lots of examples of our three sign phrase.
假设我们包括 3 个手势短语的许多例子
In our original example on training in HMM in data, we assume that the data for
在我们隐马尔可夫模型数据训练的例子中 我们假设模型 I 的
an isolated version of the sign for
单独手势数据
I was evenly divided among its three states.
平均分布在三个状态中
We then calculated the output probabilities given that assumption,
然后我们根据假设计算输出概率
adjusted the boundaries and transition probabilities, and
调整分界线和转移概率
iterated until convergence.
然后迭代 直到收敛到一点
&gt;&gt; We're going to do the same thing for our first step here, but
— 我们第一步同样这么做
this time we will assume that the data is evenly divided between each sign, and
但是这次我们假设数据平均分布在每个手势中
then we'll divide the data for each state in each sign.
并且我们对每个手势中各状态的数据进行切分
&gt;&gt; And we iterate the same way we did before,
— 然后与之前一样进行迭代
adjusting the boundaries on each state and each sign until we converge.
调整每个状态和手势的分界线 直到收敛到一点
&gt;&gt; Now's when things get interesting.
— 现在事情更加有趣了
After we've converged everything for each sign, we're going to go back and
我们收敛了每个手势的内容 然后回去
find every place where I NEED occurs.
发现 I NEED 出现的每一处
Notice that there will be a lot fewer of those than there are examples of NEED.
注意 这里比 NEED 例子中少很多
&gt;&gt; But let's assume that there are enough examples.
— 不过我们认为有足够多的例子
&gt;&gt; Okay.
— 好
Well we are going to cut out the data we think belongs to I NEED, and
我们要删除我们认为属于 I NEED 中的数据
train the combined six state model on it.
训练 6 个组合状态模型
&gt;&gt; How does that help?
— 那样有什么用途呢？
&gt;&gt; Well the output probabilities at the boundary between I and
— I 和 NEED 分界线的输出概率
NEED, here and here,
这儿和这儿
as well as the transition probabilities in that region, will be tuned to
以及这个区域的转移概率可以进行调整
better represent I NEED than the general case which would include we need.
比包括 we need 的一般情况中 更好地表现 I NEED
In speech the effect of one phoneme affecting the adjacent phoneme is called
在语音中 影响临近音素的某个音素效果
coarticulation, and this method of modeling is called context training.
称为协同发音 这种建模方法叫做上下文训练
&gt;&gt; So I see we're going to do the same thing for NEED CAT1.
— 我发现我们要对 NEED CAT1 进行相同的操作
&gt;&gt; Yep, and for every other two sign combination.
— 没错 对于其他两个手势组合
NEED-CAT2, WANT-CAT1, WANT-CAT2, I-WANT, WE-NEED, and WE-WANT.
NEED 和 CAT2 WANT 和 CAT1 WANT 和 CAT2 I 和 WANT WE 和 NEED 以及 WE 和 WANT
We are going to iterate using Baum-Welch, using these larger contexts
我们使用波氏重估进行迭代 从嵌入式训练中使用更大的语境
from embedded training, until we converge again.
直到我们再次收敛到一点
&gt;&gt; Why not use three sign contexts, or
— 为什么不使用三个手势语境呢？
even more when the phrases are complex enough?
或者是短语更加复杂的情况呢？
&gt;&gt; If we have enough data that's not a bad idea,
— 如果我们有足够多的数据 这是个不错的主意
because the benefits are actually pretty large.
因为优点实际上更大
For recognition tasks, where there's a language structure,
对于识别任务 对于语言结构的地方
we expect context training to divide our error rate in half.
我们希望进行上下文训练 把误差率降到一半